After all the excitement of using
太好了
your coworkers laptops as a makeshift distributed cluster,
你征用同事们的电脑做了个临时的分布式集群
you almost forgot the whole point.
但别忘了重点
You're trying to find the top artists for your Canadian users.
你要找到加拿大用户最喜爱的歌手
So far, we've filtered out the activity from
目前为止 我们已经把
non Canadian users and extracted the artist's name.
非加拿大用户剔除并且提取出了歌手的名字
We still need to sum up the number of times each artist
我们还要把每个歌手的出现次数加总
appears and sort this to find the top artists.
然后排序找到最受欢迎的歌手
Since you only need the artist's name and
因为你只要歌手的名字
Canadians only make up a small part of your users,
而考虑到加拿大的用户数量也只占总用户量的一小部分
the results that your coworkers email back to you only add up to 10 gigs of data.
所以最终你同事返回的数据加起来只有 10 个G
This data won't fit into the memory on your single machine.
当然你的内存无法一次容纳这么多数据
So, as it big data, as it turns out,
所以这仍算大数据
it's easier to use your own laptop to solve this,
但实际上 你用一台电脑来处理会更加方便
even though it would take more than 10 gigs of memory to sort the artist,
虽然需要超过 10 G 的内存来给歌手排序
since sorting as a superlinear algorithm.
毕竟排序是个超线性的算法
This problem doesn't require us to sort all 10 gigabytes.
但是这个问题并不需要我们给 10 G 的数据都排序
A program could start by summing up the number of times
我们可以写个程序先把每个歌手的出现次数
each artist appears and we end up with one sum for each artist.
加总得到每个歌手出现总数的数据
Rather than dealing with millions of numbers,
这样我们就不用处理数百万的数据了
we only need to sort the artists,
只需要处理加总后的歌手数据
and there's probably only a few thousand of them,
或许只有几千个歌手呢
a few measly kilobytes.
也就小几千字节吧
Once we have this intermediate result,
当我们得到了这个中间结果时
we can easily sort this in your laptop's memory.
就可以用电脑的内存来做排序了
But how do you get this intermediate result?
但我们如何得到这个中间结果呢
One clever trick is to start by writing a very simple program that
一个小窍门就是先写个简单的小程序
separates all the data for the artists whose name begins with A through M,
把名字从 A 到 M 开头的歌手单独成组
from all the artists from the latter half of the alphabet.
剩下的歌手为另一组
After that step, you can fit each half,
结束之后 你就可以把每组数据读取到内存里
which will be roughly five gigs each,
大概 5 个 G 吧
into your memory and you can sum up each artist independently.
然后对每个歌手的出现次数加总
It's tempting to assume that if your dataset is bigger than your computer's memory,
当数据集大于内存时 我们会不自觉的认为
it's automatically big data.
这就是大数据
But this example shows it's more complicated than that.
但是这个例子告诉我们 情况往往不那么简单
It can go the other way too.
这也不一定是大数据
Sometimes you have a smaller dataset,
有时你的数据比较小
maybe only two gigs,
或许只有 2 G
but you want to do something sophisticated,
但是你需要做一些非常复杂的运算
like training a deep learning model.
比如训练一个深度学习模型
This may be easier to do with more hardware,
或许多些硬件会更好
and thus would qualify as big data.
这也可以说是大数据
This is why there's no simple definition for big data.
所以说大数据没有简单明了的定义
But if you understand the capabilities of your computer,
但是只要你清楚你电脑的性能
then you can decide when you have big data and when it makes sense to use Spark.
你就知道什么时候是大数据以及什么时候该用 Spark 了